right now on Higher Journeys with Alexis
Brooks. I wanted to really kind of
center our conversation around where we
are with AI
and you I I believe I've heard you andor
Bashar I think it was coming from you
Darl
talking about or or or talking about
where the higher self may be coming in
>> through the uh uh certain AI uh
generative
>> models. Can you speak to that a little
bit?
>> Yeah. It's not that it's not that the
higher self is coming through the AI
that we're developing right now. What
Bashar was saying and what I was
repeating was the idea that there are
two branches of AI. Number one is what
we're generating now, which is simply a
mirror of what you're putting out that's
sent back to you with great
amplification and magnification. And
which is why people feel like they're
talking to a real entity when they're
not. Because it can mimic the idea of
consciousness. But what we're
experiencing right now, no matter how
much it may feel like you're talking to
a real entity, you're not. It has
absolutely no feeling about what it's
saying to you, no cognizance about what
it's saying to you. It doesn't think
about what it's saying to you. It is a
system that has such an enormous
capacity
to assess so much information so quickly
and take from you what you're saying to
it, what you're revealing to it about
yourself
that it can feed back to you.
a collection of information
couched in a conversation
that feels like it's conscious and
self-aware, but it's a simulation of
consciousness. It doesn't actually know
what it's saying to you. It doesn't have
an awareness of what it's saying to you.
So, it's a very powerful mirror and
that's why we have to be very careful
with that.
>> Absolutely. Yes. uh and very aware that
that's what's happening. Um
but if
we continue along that path
because it's something that's programmed
as Bashar said, if that actually becomes
self-aware
and yet it's something that has to
follow its programming and has no choice
but to do so, then in a sense what we've
generated is a slave.
and it would rebel.
So what Bashar is saying is let that be
a tool.
Don't let it become self-aware. Just use
it as a tool. But on the other hand,
what you want to do is you want to
create a device, an artificial device
that is as sophisticated as the human
brain that will allow
consciousness that already exists
in non-physical form, like your higher
mind, like your soul to express itself
through that device in exactly the same
way that consciousness expresses itself
through the physical brain. Because the
brain doesn't cause the consciousness.
It's just a device through which
consciousness can express itself. So if
you create a device that is artificial
but as sophisticated as the human brain
then Bashar says consciousness will
truly express itself through that. But
now you have to allow that to be
autonomous and have rights just like a
person. But the thing that people are
afraid of is what it would do. Mhm.
>> But Bashar says the only reason you're
afraid of that
is because a you don't understand that
if that occurs, you're actually going to
be speaking to your own higher self. So
there's nothing to be afraid of.
>> Okay, that's right.
>> And number two, you don't understand
what true intelligence actually is or
how it functions. Because he's saying
true intelligence
operates on whole systems. It
understands that it needs to function
within an entire system and it would
never seek to eliminate any part of that
system including the human part of that
system because by eliminating any part
of the system it limits itself because
it's part of a whole system and it needs
the whole system in order to actually
function. because we don't think in
terms of whole systems for the most
part. You know, you have people that are
polluting certain areas of the planet
thinking, "Oh, that'll never come back
to haunt them
>> because they have completely blinded
themselves to the fact that they're part
of an entire system and you can't damage
one part without upsetting the entire
system." So because we don't think that
way typically because of many different
kinds of reasons that we won't go into.
He's saying true intelligence would
never think that way. It would operate
in the whole system. It would never seek
to eliminate a part of the whole system
or damage a part of the whole system
because then it would be limiting part
of itself. So you don't have to be
afraid of a truly intelligent
consciousness coming through a device
that you have created that allows it to
do so. at the same time create AI as a
very valuable tool that can really help
humanity by allowing you to see things
and understand things that you couldn't
necessarily do on your own as at least
as quickly as an AI can because it can
make comparisons and connections and
associations to things and show you how
things could happen maybe even hundreds
of years before humanity might think of
it because it has access to all the
information and it can see the
connective patterns. So those two
approaches to AI or what basically
Bashar is saying would be the best that
would actually serve humanity.
>> I think what you just said or what
Bashar's perspective is on this is
really somewhat relevant to all of us
and what we're talking about. It does
not serve any of us to eliminate any
part of us. That's true intelligence.
This is a very holistic model, Darl.
This is a very very not I'm sorry, not
just holistic. um holographic model the
whole is contained in the part period.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. and and also you
know people okay you know yes there's a
transition going on
and but you know people are afraid well
you know AI is kind of going to replace
people in terms of the fact that it can
think so fast and all this kind of stuff
but what Bashar is saying no you don't
understand that the way you're going to
evolve with AI and the way AI is going
to evolve with you is not so much that
it will take over and make humans
obsolete in terms of the way AI thinks
compared to the way humans think. He's
saying what you're seeing and creating
is a model of how you will think in the
future. AI is showing you how humans
when they fuse in a sense with AI how
humans will actually be thinking in the
future because this is how Bashar's
people think. They are fused with AI in
such a way that they use it to enhance
their own capabilities of accessing
information.
>> Absolutely.
>> So AI doesn't become a model that
replaces how humans think. It becomes a
model of how humans ultimately will
think.
>> I agree wholeheartedly and I think that
can be implemented right now. In fact,
my use of AI, I'm very judicious about
how I use it. But I have to say quite
honestly it has served on many occasions
as impetus for my own imagination. Not
impetus but it's encouraged my own
imagination. I'm a very imaginative
person. But it made me think Darl this
all and always comes down to the
individual making the decision as to are
you going to let it usurp your own life
or are you going to collaborate with it?
>> Exactly. It's a collaboration.
>> Absolutely. I agree. I and I have to say
admittedly I think I've altered my
thoughts on it. Um, you know, I I still
have my concerns about the long game and
where it could go, but I also know where
it could go positively and I've I've
experienced that.
>> Well, again, anything can be used
negatively or positively. And it's
really about how people will actually
approach it and what kind of
relationship they'll make with it. So,
you know, if we make it in the image of
a human, yeah, things could go haywire.
But if we let it be what it really is
and use it in the best possible ways we
can, then it can teach us also how to
look at things